还适应吗
How are you settling in?
挺好的
Pretty well.
普林斯顿的校区很棒
Princeton has a beautiful campus.
我学了几个新泽西的有趣小知识
Now, I've learned some fun facts about New Jersey
你能拿去跟别人打开话题
to help you make small talk.
你想知道他们的州鸟或谋杀率吗
Would you like to know the state bird or the murder rate?
说出来都会吓你一跳
They're both shocking.
其实我想听的是你的事
Actually, I want to hear about you.
你那边还好吗
How are things at home?
我这边看到东部金翅雀
Well, I'm a lot less likely to see an Eastern Goldfinch
或者被谋杀的几率肯定比你低
or be murdered, I'll tell you that.
我想你
I miss you.
我也想你
I miss you, too.
有件事很奇怪
It's so strange,
今天早先我用介词结尾了一个句子
earlier today I ended a sentence with a preposition
而你却不在我身边纠正我语法
and you weren't there to correct my grammar.
我对你这遭遇感到抱歉
I'm sorry you had to go through that.
其实呢
In fact,
我正是因为这事而开始想念你
that's when I started to really miss you.
你刚才分裂了不定式
You know you just split an infinitive.
是吗
Did I?
你要好好教育我吗
Are you gonna teach me a lesson?
当然要
I am.
你这样很不乖
It is naughty to put an adverb
在"to"跟动词之间插入副词
between the word "to" and the verb stem.
那你要怎么惩罚我啊
What are you gonna do about it?
我要告诫你
I'm going to admonish you.
狠狠地告诫吗
Vigorously?
我也只会这么告诫人
That's the only kind of admonishing I do.
艾米走后  谢尔顿还好吗
How's Sheldon doing with Amy gone?
最近三个晚上
Well, the last three nights
我带他去剪了头发
I've had to take him to get a haircut,
去火车模型店  去了隔壁市还有在卖
to the train store, and to a Walgreens in Arcadia
"好版本布洛芬止痛药"的连锁药店
where they still have the "Good ibuprofen."
现在问问我  艾米走后  我还好吗
Now ask me how I'm doing with Amy gone.
-艾米走后你还...  -闭嘴
- How are you doing with... - Shut up.
如果有需要  我们可以帮忙啊
If you'd like, we can help you out.
那就太好了
Oh, that would be great.
不是我帮你  我是有老婆孩子的忙人了
I mean, not me, I've got a wife and child,
但这家伙闲到在社交媒体上发牙线洁牙的视频
but this one posts video of himself flossing on Instagram.
我发的是教程好吗
It was a tutorial.
可以  我很乐意陪陪谢尔顿
And yes, I'm happy to keep Sheldon company.
太好了  今晚他想去家居店看看梯子
Great. Tonight he wants to look at ladders at Home Depot.
他为什么会需要梯子
Oh, why does he need a ladder?
他不需要  他就是喜欢看看
He doesn't; he just likes looking at them.
记得带本书打发时间
Bring a book.
各位
Gentlemen.
还记得诺维茨基博士吗
You may remember Dr. Nowitzki,
她又回来加州理工读博士后啦
She's back at Caltech for her postdoc.
-你好啊  -你们好
- Hello. - Hello.
我去帮你拿张椅子
Oh, let me bring a chair for you.
谢谢
Oh, thanks.
诺维茨基博士要跟我说说
Dr. Nowitzki's going to tell me
她在欧洲核子研究中心的研究
about the work she did at CERN.
而且她还给我带了免税三角巧克力
And she brought me this duty-free Toblerone.
我好爱吃这个
Oh. I love those.
我们坐别桌吧
Let's sit somewhere else.
刚发生什么事了
What just happened?
一个陌生人用巧克力棒诱拐走了谢尔顿
A stranger just lured Sheldon away with a candy bar.
等等  她不是以前一直围着他转的女研究生吗
Wait, isn't she the grad student that used to follow him around?
是呢
Oh, yeah.
在他还没进入青春期  鸡鸡没发育的时候
Back before he hit puberty and grew man parts.
你们觉得他们有什么猫腻
So what do you guys think that's about?
据我对谢尔顿的了解  啥都没有
Knowing Sheldon, nothing.
跟我说说你的标量场暗能量实验
So, tell me about your scalar dark energy experiment.
你先跟我说说你最新的论文
Not 'til you tell me about your latest paper
圈量子理论
on quantum loop theory.
你肯定是那种要先吃甜点才吃正餐的人
You must be one of those dessert before dinner people.
他居然引她发笑了  果真是有猫腻
He just made her laugh, something's wrong.
你们看到她看他的眼神了吗
Do you see the way she's looking at him?
看到了  就像当年伯纳黛特看我那样
Yeah. Like Bernadette used to look at me.
我跟你说过多少次了  关上浴室门
I keep telling you, close the bathroom door.
你们看到了吗
Ah, did you see that?
她摸了他的手  他都没甩开
She just touched his hand and he didn't swat it away.
到底怎么回事
What is happening?
最简单的解释通常也是最正确的解释
Okay, the simplest explanation is usually the right one.
什么解释
Which is?
那不是谢尔顿
That ain't Sheldon.
他们不止共进午餐
Not only did they eat together,
莱纳德说谢尔顿还把她逗乐了
Leonard said he made her laugh.
那不算什么
That's nothing,
华仔说她还碰了谢尔顿的手
Howie said she touched his hand.
他用洗手液清洁了吗
Did he Purell?
并没有
No.
真不敢相信莱纳德提了三角巧克力
I cannot believe Leonard mentioned the Toblerone
却没提到这个
but left that part out.
我们该打给艾米吗
Should we call Amy?
不知道  如果没什么的话我们不该让她担心
I don't know; we shouldn't worry her if it's nothing.
那我们再等等
I guess we could wait
-等掌握多一点这妹子的情况再说  -行
- till we have more information about this girl. - Yeah.
你觉得跟艾米住在一起
Do you think living with Amy
会不会莫名其妙激起谢尔顿的...
has somehow stirred up Sheldon's...
性欲
sexual appetite?
你怎么能有那种想法
How can you think that?
这么恶心的句子你居然也说得出来
Why would you even put those words together?
好啦  那我们达成共识
All right, then we agree.
他不会采取任何行动
He's not making any moves,
是那个博士妞拉蒙娜太主动
it's this Dr. Ramona chick.
诺维茨基  我上网查了她  人还挺俏
Nowitzki. I Googled her, she's pretty cute.
是吗  莱纳德只告诉我
Really? All I got from Leonard
三角巧克力棒里有坚果仁
was the Toblerone bar had nuts.
听这个
And get this,
我看见一把折叠关节梯
I saw an articulating ladder
带双腿水平校准  可以在不平坦的地面
with dual-leg leveling, which delivers stability
提供稳定性和适应性
and adaptability to uneven terrain.
听起来今晚过得很充实啊
Sounds like a big night.
对啊  拉杰还讲了一个超好笑的笑话
Yeah. Raj made the funniest joke, he said,
他说"哪一把梯子最适合拿来自杀上吊"
"Which is the best ladder to use to hang myself?"
所以你一直都有事情做  你不会孤单吗
So you're keeping busy? You're not lonely?
完全不会
Oh, not at all.
我傍晚跟莱纳德和拉杰一起外出
I've had outings with Leonard and Raj in the evening,
对了  我还跟诺维茨基博士一起吃了午餐
and-- oh, I had lunch with Dr. Nowitzki.
他是谁
Who's he?
诺维茨基博士是女的
Oh, Dr. Nowitzki is a woman.
是吗
Oh. Really?
你什么时候认识她的
Uh, when did you meet her?
很多年前吧
Many years ago.
那会她还是研究生
Back when she was a grad student.
她一直对我的研究超级感兴趣
She's always been a huge fan of my work,
现在她在加州理工学院做研究
and now she's doing research at Caltech.
超级迷妹  是吧
Huge fan, you say?
是的  我觉得你会喜欢她
Yes. I think you'd like her.
她冰雪聪明  就跟你一样
She's extremely intelligent, just like you.
跟你不一样的是  她是金发高妹
Unlike you, she's tall, blonde
之前还是奥运会的游泳选手
and used to be an Olympic swimmer.
太棒了  我很快打回来给你
That's terrific. I'll call you right back.
艾米
Oh, hey, Amy.
我就让你们做一件事
I gave you one job!
帮我看着他
Keep an eye on him.
是有多难
How hard is that?
我们以为你说的看着他
We thought you meant
是别让他瞎跑到车流中
not letting him run out into traffic.
-他就瞎跑过一次  -对
- Which he only did once. - Yeah.
你们为什么不告诉我
Why didn't you tell me?
我们不想让你担心啊
We didn't want you to worry.
我该担心吗
Should I worry?
不用  拜托  那可是谢尔顿
No. Come on, it's Sheldon.
什么事都不会发生
Nothing is gonna happen.
我一开始跟他约会时  你也是这么说的
That's what you said to me when I started dating him.
现在五年过去了
And then five years later,
结果咧结果咧  有事发生了吧
bingo-bango, something happened.
是啊  但你三个月后就回来啦
Yeah, but you're gonna be back in three months.
你们不会明白
You don't get it.
那瓶番茄酱的屁股  老娘已经费劲拍了那么久
I've been smacking that ketchup bottle for a long time.
现在那女的只需要将它倒过来
All she's got to do is tip it over
对准她的薯条就能享受现成的了
and point it at her fries.
那你希望我们怎么做
Well, what do you want us to do?
我不知道
I don't know.
可能受了新泽西州讲话方式的影响
Might be the New Jersey talking,
但这个诺维茨基浪蹄子必须消失
but this Nowitzki broad needs to disappear.
用不用这样啊
That's ridiculous.
据我们所知
As far as we know,
就是两名科学家一起吃午餐
all that happened is two scientists had lunch.
是啊  可其中一名科学家
Yeah, but one of those scientists
是一名金发高妹的奥运游泳选手
is a tall, blonde Olympic swimmer.
拜托  外表对谢尔顿来说不重要
Come on. Looks don't matter to Sheldon.
因为他的眼中只有你
Because he only has eyes for you.
少拍马屁
Nice try.
多谢  我胡乱拼凑瞎说的
Thanks. I was scrambling.
真是不可理喻
It's unbelievable.
谢尔顿跟其他别人吃午餐
Sheldon has lunch with another woman
而我老婆居然把我吼了一顿
and somehow my wife yells at me.
佩妮也把我骂了一顿
Penny laid into me, too.
显然  我过分专注在
Apparently, I'm overly fixated on
优质的瑞士巧克力棒上
premium Swiss chocolate bars.
你应该不能吃那玩意吧
Can you even eat those things?
提前一个半小时吃一片防胀气咀嚼片
If I take a Lactaid a half-hour before
吃完后马上吃止泻药就没事啊
and some Pepto right after.
听起来很麻烦啊
Sounds like a lot of work.
是啊  但也值了
Yeah. Eh, I'm worth it.
伙计们  别偏题
Guys. Focus.
我们该对诺维茨基采取行动吗
Should we do something about Nowitzki?
比如什么
Like what?
她现在单身
Uh, well, she's single,
所以如果其他人约她出去  她答应的话
so if somebody else asks her out and she says yes,
就证明她对谢尔顿没兴趣
then we know she's not into Sheldon.
我上吧
I'll do it.
无意冒犯  斯图尔特
No offense, Stuart,
但那位女性是个博士[医生]
but th-th-the woman's a doctor.
那又如何  医生都喜欢我
So? Doctors like me.
我每次去找我的医生看病
Whenever I see mine he calls in
他都叫很多其他医生进来看我
a bunch of other doctors to have a look.
她不是那种医生
She's not that kind of doctor.
那是她的损失
Well, her loss.
人称真医学奇葩就是我
I've been called a genuine medical oddity.
其实我本来是想毛遂自荐
Actually, I was going to suggest me.
太好了  谁都比那谁强
Great. Anybody's better than, mmm.
不好意思
Excuse me.
他们只取走了我的脾脏和胆囊
They took out my spleen and gallbladder,
我的情感还在
not my feelings.
诺维茨基博士
Dr. Nowitzki.
-很高兴见到你  -我也是
- Good to see you. - Good to see you, too.
我能和你一起坐吗
May I join you?
不能
No.
很高兴见到你
Good to see you.
我们应该打给吉尼斯  那可能破了被拒绝速度的记录
We should call Guinness, that might be a record.
她一看就是正在吃工作午餐
She's clearly having a working lunch
不希望被打扰
and preferred to eat alone.
库珀博士  这边
Dr. Cooper, over here.
我本来可以让她很开心的
I could have made her very happy.
你乖乖走开  我想她应该开心了
You kept walking. I think you did.
你真觉得我们有理由担心吗
Do you really think there's reason to worry?
是啊  她绝对在倒追谢尔顿
Yeah, she's definitely going after Sheldon.
我勾引过她  但她拒绝我了
I made a play for her and she shot me down.
可那根本证明不了什么
All right, well, that doesn't prove anything.
是啊  女人有一百万个拒绝拉杰的原因
Yeah, there's a million reasons a woman would shoot Raj down.
真的吗  一百万个那么夸张
Like, really, a million?
好吧  几百个
Fine, hundreds.
谢谢你啊
Thank you.
重点是  这可能根本没什么
The point is this could be nothing
我们都反应过度了
and we are all overreacting.
大家好
Hey, everybody.
这位是我朋友
This is my friend,
-诺维茨基博士  -大家好
- Dr. Nowitzki. - Hi.
你好
Hi.
我们刚去游泳了
We just went swimming.
你真的进泳池里了吗
And you actually got in a pool?
我一开始怕得要死
I was scared,
但我告诉自己  这只是个大浴缸
but I told myself it's just a big bathtub.
然后我再度怕得要死
Then I got scared again 'cause there are
因为我浴缸里有很多陌生人
all these strangers in my bathtub.
我为他感到骄傲
I was proud of him-- a lot of people
很多人第一天都不敢把脸埋进水里
don't put their face in the water on the first day.
我是为了躲避一只蜜蜂  但那也算数
Well, I was hiding from a bee, but it still counts.
麻烦让个位子给我
Can I just squeeze in here?
谢尔顿  你跟艾米联系过了吗
So, Sheldon, have you talked to Amy?
有啊  我们今早视频聊天了
Yes, we Skyped this morning
我睡前会再跟她联系一次
and I'm sure I'll check in with her before I go to sleep.
谢尔顿总说起她
Sheldon talks about her all the time.
我等不及见她了
I can't wait to meet her.
真的
That is true.
她一直在问艾米会离开多久
She keeps asking how long Amy's going to be gone.
拉蒙娜  自我介绍一下吧
Uh, so, Ramona, tell us about yourself.
你有男朋友吗
Do you, do you have a boyfriend?
莱纳德  你老婆就坐在旁边
Leonard, your wife is sitting right here.
你干嘛呢
What are you doing?
我的工作很忙  没什么时间谈恋爱
No, my work doesn't leave me a lot of time for relationships.
这一点你已经表达得很清楚了
I think you made that very clear.
她曾是欧洲核子研究中心美国团队的一员
She was part of the American team at CERN.
他们探测到希格斯玻色子时  我就在现场
I had a front row seat when they detected the Higgs boson.
你知道吗
Do you know,
我和彼得·希格斯通过信
I've corresponded with Peter Higgs.
英国理论物理学家  提出了希格斯机制
曾获诺贝尔物理学奖
你想看看他的信吗
Would you like to see some of his letters?
-当然了  -我去拿
- Absolutely. - I'll get them.
等等  我跟你一起去
Well, hang on, I'll come with you.
真好玩
Oh, fun.
像玩耍约会一样
Like a play date.
如果我说错了  纠正我
Okay, correct me if I'm wrong, but isn't that exactly
但我们不是该阻止这种事的发生吗
what we were supposed to stop from happening?
我都舍身用肉体隔开他们了
I threw my body at them,
你还想要我怎么样
what else did you want me to do?
你觉得你该打电话给艾米吗
You think you should call Amy?
你有手有嘴  你打啊
You got fingers and a mouth, you call her.
你看
Here you go.
这些信都是彼得·希格斯写给你的吗
Are these all from Peter Higgs?
不不不
Oh, no, no, no.
有很多不同的名人
They're from many famous people.
看到没  比如这封信
See? Oh, like this one.
来自帕特里克·斯图尔特
This is from Patrick Stewart.
信上说  如果我再去他家
It says if I come to his house again,
他就会放狗来跟我"会一会"
I get to meet his dogs.
不好意思
Oh, excuse me.
-你好  谢尔顿  -你好  艾米
- Hello, Sheldon. - Oh, hello, Amy.
我又想你了
I was missing you again.
我也想你
I miss you, too.
时机正好
Hey, this is good timing.
还记得我之前跟你提过的诺维茨基博士吗
Remember that Dr. Nowitzki I told you about?
她就在这儿呢
She's right here.
她什么
Sh-she's what?
你好
Hello.
Hi.
幸会
So nice to meet you.
稍等
Hang on.
喂
Hello.
有点迟了  莱纳德
A little late, Leonard.
对不起
I'm sorry.
莱纳德这个时候打电话给你做什么
What is Leonard doing calling you at this hour?
这不重要
It's not important.
我得跟你说  这样似乎有点不合适
I must tell you, that seems a little inappropriate.
你同意吗
Don't you agree?
同意
I do.
瞧
See?
我们都这样认为
We both think so.
好了  我快疯了
All right, this is making me crazy.
你们谁过去一下
Somebody's got to go over there.
你有腿有脚  你去啊
You got feet and legs, you do it.
你要和我一起去吗
Will you go with me?
去了做什么  冲他们摇硬币罐吗
To do what? Shake a can of nickels at them?
我们太杞人忧天了
We're being ridiculous.
那么漂亮的女人是不可能
There's no way a woman that attractive
试图勾引谢尔顿·库珀的
is trying to seduce Sheldon Cooper.
你的自我安慰牌打完了没
You done trying to make yourself feel better?
没  我还没打种族歧视牌呢
No. I haven't played the race card yet.
我也不想打断聚会
Hey, I hate to break up the party,
但艾米说我累了  必须上床睡觉
but Amy says I'm tired and have to go to bed.
很高兴见到大家
It was nice seeing everybody.
多谢你们的晚餐
Thank you for dinner.
-不客气  -我们的荣幸
- Sure. - Our pleasure.
随便啦
Whatever.
要送我上车吗
Walk me to my car?
当然
Of course.
我们一起送
We'll all go.
借过
Excuse me.
不好意思  我过去下  好了
Pardon. I just need to... yeah.
真好玩
That was fun.
像玩"马里奥赛车"
It was like Mario Kart.
拜
Bye.
我们需要谈谈
We need to talk.
是关于莱纳德和艾米的事吗
Wh-- Is this about Leonard and Amy?
我也不爽
I don't like it either.
我知道你在女人方面经验不足
Okay, I know you don't have a lot of experience with women,
但拉蒙娜似乎
but Ramona seems to have
对你有意思
a romantic interest in you.
这根本没道理
That doesn't make any sense.
她知道我有女朋友
She knows I have a girlfriend.
有时候女人不在乎
Well, sometimes women don't care.
有时候这令她们更想要这个男人
Sometimes it makes them want a guy even more.
可能是这样
That may be true,
但诺维茨基博士只是朋友
but Dr. Nowitzki's just a friend.
事实上  如果她没穿那件突显
In fact, I wouldn't have even noticed she's a woman
她胸部的泳衣的话  我都没注意到她是女人
if she hadn't worn that bathing suit that highlighted her bosom.
好吧  我们换个说法
Okay. Um... ...let's try this.
把你自己想象成那种
Think of yourself as one of those
人们喜欢收集的限量版玩具公仔
limited edition toys people like to collect.
我一直是这样想的
I already do.
那你就会明白了
Well, then you get it.
因为我是独一无二的
Because there's only one of me,
我更有价值
I'm more valuable.
对了
Right.
不过  艾米已经把我从包装盒中拿出来
Although, Amy's already taken me out of my package
玩过了  我掉价了
and played with me.
别管玩具这个比喻了
Let's forget the toy thing, okay?
-也许  -佩妮  感谢你的关心
- Um, maybe... - Penny, look. I appreciate your concern,
但我不觉得事情是这样的
but I don't think that's what's happening.
好吧  你觉得事情是怎样的
All right. What do you think is happening?
我觉得诺维茨基博士是一位友好的同事
I think Dr. Nowitzki is a friendly colleague.
我觉得你和莱纳德需要见婚姻咨询师
I think you and Leonard need to see a marriage counselor.
我需要去更新简历
And I need to update my resume
加上游泳这项特殊技能
to include swimming as a special skill.
别这样看着我  我尽力了
Don't look at me like that, I tried.
你吃了吗
Hey, did you eat yet?
吃了早餐  没吃中餐
Uh, breakfast yes, lunch no.
我服用了止咳糖
I did have a cough drop,
但这是介于吸和吃之间的行为
but that really rides the line between sucking and eating.
太好了  我给咱俩做了三明治
Well, perfect. I made us sandwiches.
真是周到
How thoughtful.
谢谢你
Thank you.
没什么
No big deal,
我喜欢和你在一起
I enjoy spending time with you.
我也是
And I with you.
问一下
Question:
你是想和我发展恋爱关系吗
are you seeking a romantic relationship with me?
如果我是呢
What if I were?
这会引起一系列的问题
Well, that would raise a number of problems.
我们是同事
We're colleagues.
我现在有女友
I'm currently in a relation...
恕我失陪一下
Excuse me a moment.
艾米
Amy.
你愿意嫁给我吗
Will you marry me?